<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yue Linn's personal site</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/</link><description>Recent content on Yue Linn's personal site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/skeleton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/skeleton/</guid><description>The team and our prototype.
Active year(s):</description></item><item><title>Adipose Stem Cells Harvesting</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/adipose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/adipose/</guid><description>This project was done during an internship under NUS in collaboration with Biopolis. This project aimed to assist scientists by automating the preparation of adipose tissue for stem cell extration.
The adipose tissue must be broken down into smaller pieces to optimise the yield of the extraction process. However, the cells are prone to damaged if handled too aggresively. Hence, gear-like teeth were used to break down the tissue. I was tasked to design, fabricate, and test the prototype.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Bus Project</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/bus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/bus/</guid><description>Simulation of bus in Gazebo.
I was the lead of the perception team for the Autonomous Bus project. This project was funded by the Land Transport Agency of Singapore (LTA) in collaboration with ST Engineering and A*STAR. Our team developed and implemented the software stack which detects, classifies, tracks, and predicts trajectories of dynamic obstacles for a self-driving bus. My main contributions are as follows:
I developed the Robotic Operating System (ROS) sensor drivers for the embedded system on-board the bus.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Underground Train Tracks Inspection Robot</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/mrt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/mrt/</guid><description>The team and our prototype.
This robot performed safety inspections in tunnels for underground trains. This was my Final-Year-Project for my undergraduate degree. The project was selected to be presented at the International Senior Project Conference 2017 in Thailand. My contributions to the project were as follows:
I developed the thermal image processing methods to automate the detection of leaks in train tunnels. I programmed the Arduino microprocessor to interface with the gyroscope and accelerometer sensors to automate the inspection of the cross slope of the train rails.</description></item><item><title>Concrete Air Cannon</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/cannon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/cannon/</guid><description>This project was done during my intership at HOPE Technik Pte Ltd. The aim of the project was to test the strength of concrete blocks at high impact. To do so, I was tasked to build a system that will project the concrete blocks at high speed. The developed system is an &amp;ldquo;air cannon&amp;rdquo; that uses pressurised air to shoot the concrete blocks out from a barrel. Specificalluy, my contribution is in conceptualizing, designing, manufacturing and testing the air cannon.</description></item><item><title>Donkeycar Project @ NUS</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/donkeycar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/donkeycar/</guid><description>Frame of a Donkeycar
I was the lead of the perception team for the Autonomous Bus project. Our team developed and implemented the software stack which detects, This project introduced high school students to the field of robotics, through hands-on learning of electronics, Python, and deep learning. The curriculum was based on the Donkeycar project which aims to make remote control (RC) cars autonomous. My role as a mentor in this project included the following:</description></item><item><title>Electric Bicycle Generator Exhibition</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/ebike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/ebike/</guid><description>To increase awareness on electricity wastage, we simulated the generation of electricity using exercise bikes. We hope that people will realise the amount of effort required to generate the electricity that we often take for granted. As part a team of multidisplinary students working on this project, I developed the Arduino code to read the signals from the exercise bikes and the display interface using Processing language. I worked on this project while I was an on an exhange programme as an undergraduate at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST).</description></item><item><title>Engineering Good Student Chapter (Technology Development Programme)</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/egsc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/egsc/</guid><description>The steps infront of the flat entrances.
Under the Engineering Good Student Chapter (EGSC) Technology Development Programme, I was part of the team tasked to design, prototype and test a system for wheelchairs to overcome the stairs in front of older HDB flats. We worked closely with SPD to design a solution for their wheelchair-bound clients living in older public housing flats which have 2 to 4 steps leading up to their front door.</description></item><item><title>HackUST: Team FLUSH</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/hackust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/hackust/</guid><description>While I was an on an exhange programme as an undergraduate at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST), I participated in their hackathon, HackUST. During the hackathon, I joined Team FLUSH which aims to solve the excessive queuing problem at female toilets. I was the team&amp;rsquo;s Coder, so I designed and developed the Android interface for the displays to indicate queues at nearby toilets.
Team FLUSH.
Active year(s): 2016</description></item><item><title>HEAL Hackathon</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/heal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/heal/</guid><description>Under the HEAL Hackathon, I was part of a team who aimed to provide an intuitive user interface for data entry and analysis during post disaster relief efforts for Save the Children. Our solution was to use VBA in Microsoft Excel to store data from survey forms.
Active year(s): 2015</description></item><item><title>Project Nancy</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/nancy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/nancy/</guid><description>Technology is almost obssed with new ideas. However, with all the cool inventions, we sometimes forget to consider how those older than us would interact with our designs. Knowing this, I started this side project for my grandmother, Nancy, who wanted to watch videos on a regular laptop.
The main challenge came from the input interfaces of the laptop. Mouses and track pads were not intuitive and unfamiliar to the elderly.</description></item><item><title>Redbull Land Rover</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/redbull/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/redbull/</guid><description>This project was done under my intership at HOPE Technik Pte Ltd in the Special Vehicle Operations (SVO) Unit. My task was to design and manufacture vehicle modifications to add features for the RedBull Land Rover.
The CAD of the modifications to the Land Rover.
Active year: 2015</description></item><item><title>Soft Robotic Catheter</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/soft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/soft/</guid><description>This project was done during an internship under NUS with collaboration with the NUH. This project aims to develop an automated catheter to assist surgeons during non-invasive surgeries. I was tasked to develop an actuation system using soft robotics as a means of actuation for catheters used in non-invasive surgeries such as in heart operations. The robot developed had to be small to fit into the arteries of a human yet move with high precision at the command of the surgeon.</description></item><item><title>The Hydrone Project</title><link>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/hydrone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuelinn-v2.onrender.com/hydrone/</guid><description>Quadcopter on water surface.
The Hydrone is an UAV developed for water environments. I was part of a multidisciplinary team of students working on this project. My main contribution is the mechanical design and fabrication of the waterproof chassis. The project was presented at Maker Faire Singapore. Our team also won the runner up at the Intel Invent 50.
Active years: 2015-2016</description></item></channel></rss>